Oreofe Stephen ADEYEMI

Phone: +1 (682)-563-1424 | Email: exxella3@gmail.com Address: 1001 Greenway Glen Dr Apt 2523 Arlington TX 76012 USA

LINKS

GitHub: https://github.com/adey-px LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/adey-px

Portfolio: https://eportfolio.mygreatlearning.com/oreofe-stephen-adeyemi

PROFILE SUMMARY

Skilled in Python, SQL and JavaScript with experience working with XML, Sass, REST APIs, RDBMS, NoSQL, JSON, Big data, Automated systems, CI/CD pipelines, Microservices, React and Vue, backend frameworks (Django and Flask), Cloud infrastructures on AWS, GCP, Azure and a variety of other technology areas. My background includes collaboration in the design, implementation, and maintenance of business solutions on client/server, web, and enterprise platforms.

My primary goal is to find an active role in a team of dedicated engineers, developers, project managers and other personnel to grow the business through collaboration, teamwork and exceptional services while improving my productivity, industry experience, and adding valuable contributions to the corporate task.

PERSONALITY

- Inner strength, self-motivating, and strong analytical skill
- Willing to learn new technologies, iterate quickly, and grow
- Multitasking, attention to detail and head for problem solving
- Capable of delivering exceptional customer service
- Focus, discipline, perseverance & determination to succeed
- Extra-ordinary commitment to excellence
- Strong organizational & team skills
- Enjoy solving technical challenges and care about writing quality code

EXPERIENCE

CohoTek IT Solutions (Fullstack Developer | February 2019 - December 2021)

- Participated in every aspect of software development, DevOps, security, and maintenance
- Designed and implemented RESTful web APIs, unit testing and microservices development
- Developed and maintained backend functionalities of various enterprise web applications using Python, and Diango framework
- Migrating digital products from legacy environments to modern environments leveraging
 DevOps techniques and tools: Kubernetes, Containers and Microservices-based architectures
- Worked with UI/UX designers to create highly engaging user experience for all projects
- Worked with the team to build generic and re-usable frontends with modern frontend JS frameworks (React and Angular)
- Participated in analysis, planning, and migration of older projects to latest version platform

- Developed software products in all phases of its lifecycle in Agile environment
- Worked closely with team members to meet and exceed client expectations
- Designed and implemented new features for cloud services and web applications
- Wrote automated tests and perform manual tests using established standard procedures
- Participated in peer-reviews of code solutions developed by teammates
- Assisted in planning upcoming work through the collection and documentation of user requirements, development of user stories, and estimates
- Worked with PostgreSQL & MySQL involving database design and advanced SQL Queries

Glisten International Academy (Web Developer | January 2015 - August 2018)

- Developed, deployed, and managed secured business websites and enterprise web applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript libraries and WordPress software to collect, manage and analyse students' enrollment, academic records, periodic assessment, and payment processing
- Served as in-house developer solely in charge of developing and managing web applications using python programming on AWS infrastructure including EC2, Lambda, RDS, CloudWatch, and S3 bucket for reliable and scalable data storage
- Worked with customer technical leads, customer executives, and partners to manage and deliver successful implementations of web services and cloud solutions, becoming a trusted advisor to decision-makers throughout the engagement
- Interacted with sales, partners, and customer technical stakeholders to manage project scope, priorities, deliverables, risk issues, and timelines for successful customer outcomes
- Advocated for customer needs to overcome adoption blockers and drive new features in web development based on user experiences and clients' requests that meet their unique needs
- Proposed solution architectures and manage the deployment of cloud based distributed virtualized infrastructure solutions that enhanced productivity
- Participated in the configuration of computer devices for conducting computer-based tests and assessments for students. The configuration usually involved network configuration, assigning of IP addresses, server-client setup, troubleshooting, fault-detection and providing solutions

EDUCATION

•	The University of Texas at Austin, TX - USA Post Graduate Program , Cloud Computing	2021 - 2022
•	Code Institute, Dublin - Ireland Diploma , Fullstack Software Development	2020 - 2021
•	College of Agriculture, Ibadan - Nigeria HND . Crop Production Technology	1999 - 2003

RELEVANT SKILL

- Strong ability and experience in web-markup fundamentals with XML, HTML & CSS
- Passion for responsive web applications design with Bootstrap and Material Design

- Valuable experience in designing interactive user interface with JavaScript and industry standard frontend libraries and frameworks including React, Angular
- Ability to develop, test and deploy dynamic web applications and web services
- Backend and server-side programming using Python and Django REST framework
- SQL developer experience in designing, querying & managing relational databases including SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, and Oracle DB
- Proven knowledge & experience in coding, software architecture, testing, security, networking, Information Systems, and technical solutions
- Familiar with multiple cloud services including Amazon Web Services (AWS), Microsoft Azure infrastructure and Google Cloud Platform.
- Proficiency in Agile methodology, web application deployment, microservices and best practices in software and application development
- Experience with version control using Git, GitHub, CI/CD, and other collaborative technologies
- Ability to analyze user needs and develop, test, and maintain software application solutions
- Proficient understanding of building and maintaining Python, and React projects
- Strong understanding of the JavaScript object model, DOM manipulation, CSS, and other common web development skills

ACHIEVEMENT SUMMARY

- Designed and developed new software features and product improvements
- Wrote, modified, reviewed, optimized and debug code using best practices
- Built and maintained customer-facing applications using modern web technologies
- Performed code reviews and provided feedback to team lead
- Interfaced with internal departments to investigate and resolve reported software issues
- Trained, mentored, and guided junior developers and UI designers
- Investigated and resolved technical and application problems